该死  我等的太久了
Damn it. I waited too long.
求你们了  做点什么
Please, come on, do something!
想想办法救救她啊
Come on, do something! Do something!
也救不了她
Couldn't have saved her.
你想继续嗑药是你的权利
It's your choice if you wanna go back on drugs.
你觉得我能挺过去吗
You think I can fix myself?
我只是需要知道  我们能合得来吗
I just need to know if you and I can work.
让我看看
Let me see.
没事
It's okay.
可能会感染的
It's gonna get infected.
你不会打算
Hey, you're not gonna...
果然
You are.
别  别这样
Don't--don't--
没关系的
It's okay.
我爱你
I love you.
然后呢
So now what?
一切都挺好
Everything's good.
我们不用谈论这个
We don't have to talk through it all.
我就问问表面问题
No, I meant it literally.
然后我们干嘛
Now what?
可以做早饭  或者打保龄球
We could make breakfast. We could go bowling.
也可以继续在这逍遥快活
We could stay here.
我得回家换身衣服
I have to go home and get dressed
然后去上班
and go to work.
到此为止吗
So that's it?
我希望这只是开始
I'm hoping this is the beginning of it.
嗯
Yeah.
你的助手是新来的
Your assistant's new.
可能他只是
It's a 50/50 chance he just...
找不到灯的开关在哪
can't find the light switch.
喂
Hello?
卡迪医生吗
Dr. Cuddy?
不  我是她家保姆
No, this is Dr. Cuddy's nanny.
她有点不舒服
She's, uh, feeling a little under the weather now,
今天不去上班了
so she won't be coming in today.
希望她没事
Oh. I hope she's all right.
您能帮我问一下她
Would you mind asking her if--
不行
No. Can't do that.
她被隔离在卫生间了
I'm afraid she's locked in the bathroom.
现在正是超级细菌泛滥的时候  怎么了
Terrible bug going around. What's the problem?
很抱歉打扰她
Well, I'm sorry to disturb her,
是理查森医生
but it's Dr. Richardson.
他可能也得了一样的肠型流感
He must have the same stomach flu.
他在手术室吐了
He threw up in the O.R.,
我不知道她想让我怎么做
and I'm not sure how she'd want me to
等下
Hold on a second.
我问过卡迪医生了
I've talked to Dr. Cuddy,
她希望你做三件事
and she would like you to do three things:
一  让他回家  二  给手术室消毒
One, send him home, two, sterilize the O.R.,
三  自己动动脑子
Three, use your own brain.
再见
See ya.
就是有人吐了
It's about puke.
跟天塌下来似的
That's what's so important.
吐了
Puke.
看来我不用急着回医院了
Well, I guess I don't have to rush back in.
但不管我们打算接下来干嘛
But whatever "Now what" we do decide on...
你都得先去洗个澡
It comes after you take a bath.
这儿有一个
Here's one.
25岁  男性
"25-year-old man
小腿麻木有刺痛感
"with numbness and tingling in his legs
伴有言语障碍
and a speech disorder, three--"
你们见到豪斯了吗
Anybody see House?
才十点呢
It's 10:00 A.M.
他来了就见鬼了
I'd be worried if he was here.
25岁
"25-year-old"--
昨天他的病人死后
He was in pretty bad shape yesterday
他状态很差
after his patient died.
他以前也死过病人啊
House has lost patients before.
谁没死过病人啊  他是成年人了
We all have. He's a big boy.
你没看到他昨天的样子
You didn't see him.
我们现在能做的
Best thing we can do for him now
也就是给他找个新病例来玩玩
is find him a new puzzle to solve.
所以  咱们继续讨论我的25岁
Thus bringing us back to my 25-year-old--
你是咱们这儿唯一一个
Yet you're the only person here
手里没有病例的人了
without a potential case in front of you.
我还没找到合适的
I haven't found the right one yet.
估计是因为
Oh. I-I thought maybe it was because
你在忙着申请假期
You were asking for a leave of absence
根本没空去好好看看病例吧
and wouldn't have time to see a case through.
我可什么都没说
I didn't say anything.
他确实没说  我在豪斯的桌上看到个信封
He didn't...I saw an envelope on house's desk
上面写着你的名字  我就自然而然地
with your name on it, so naturally, I...
拿蒸汽把它打开了
Steamed it open.
你有病吗
What's wrong with you?
你拿蒸汽是不想被人发现么
You steam an envelope to keep it secret.
所以我直接撕开看的
Which is why I just ripped it.
你能告诉我们你要去哪吗
You gonna tell us where you're going?
没这个打算
Sure sounds like a no.
到处都是玻璃渣
There's glass everywhere.
你不能轻轻地把镜子拿下来吗
Couldn't you have just put the mirror down nice and gentle?
没那心情
I was in a mood.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
别接
Don't get that.
可能有重要的事
It could be important.
这才是重要的事
This is important.
现在  我俩的事
Right now, we are more important
比医院的那些破事重要多了
than what's going on at the hospital.
所以  我们都把手机关了
So...I say we turn off our phones
享受我们的二人世界的早晨时光
and...give the morning to us.
好
Okay.
我去关机
I'll go turn it off.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你心不在焉了
You're distracted.
-我没  -你有
- I'm not. - Yeah, you are.
你虽然关了机  但还是在想
You turned off your phone but you're still wondering,
出什么事了
"What could it have been?
如果我上午不去医院  那些急事
What emergency will bring down the entire hospital
会把医院闹得怎么样的天翻地覆
if I decided to take the morning off?"
对不起
I'm sorry.
州政府给诊所的资金减少了
The clinic is facing reduced funding from the state.
护士Jeffrey正在第12次投诉人力资源部
Nurse Jeffrey is filing his 12th H.R. Complaint.
理查森威胁说要辞职
Richardson is threatening to quit
因为他被困在医院
Because he's basically been a prisoner at the hospital
近一个星期了
for almost a week.
-理查森  -神经外科的
- Richardson? - The neurosurgeon.
只剩他一个了
He's the only one I have right now,
所以他必须一直待在医院
which means he has to stay on the premises
不然  理论上来说
at all times, or else the hospital
我们就没有资格建立外伤中心
technically isn't a level one trauma center.
这意味着
Which means?
我得关掉急诊室
I'd have to shut down the E.R.,
把重症监护室里的病人都转移出去
transfer all of the patients out of the ICU...
好吧  打住  向后转
Okay, stop. Turn around.
-干嘛  -你得休息休息了
- Why? - 'cause you need to relax.
我们去哪
Where are we going?
我给你准备个魔法澡
I am going to make you a magical bath
有一堆的泡泡
with a lot of bubbles
还有神秘的东方香料
and eastern spices
蓝色的钻石  绿色的三叶草
and blue diamonds, green clovers...
赐予你新生
Transformative powers.
但我得单独待一会  积聚能量
But I must have solitude to focus my creative energies.
喂
Hello?
有趣的假设
Interesting factoid.
你知道如果没有神经外科的医生
Did you know that if we don't have a neurosurgeon on the premises,
所有的狗狗都会被宝宝给噎死吗
all the puppies in the world will choke to death on all the babies?
知道
Yeah.
13给你留了封信
You got a note from thirteen.
那为什么我们没有五个神外的医生
So how come we don't have, like, five neurosurgeons?
本来有三个  但Kapur退休了
Well, we had three, but Kapur retired,
Nichols去参加女儿的婚礼了
And then Nichols just took off for his daughter's wedding.
我有个好消息
I've got good news.
接下来16个小时
For the next 16 hours,
你就是新的神经外科医生了
you are the new neurosurgeon.
可我不是神经外科的啊
I'm not a neurosurgeon.
除非你真得做神外的手术  否则毫无问题
Which would matter if you actually had to do some neurosurgery.
豪斯  这可是医院
House, it's a hospital...
要做神经外科手术的几率比其它地方高多了
The odds of having to do neurosurgery are higher than in most places.
如果急救队说有脑或脊髓外伤
If an EMT calls in with a brain or spinal trauma,
让他们转去最近的医院就好了
just divert them at the nearest hospital.
你要做的只是
All you gotta do
在那晃悠  确保急诊开着
is stand around and keep the E.R. open.
这只是个行政角色  不是医生
It's an administrative problem, not a medical one.
豪斯  你到底在哪
House, where the hell are you?
好  很高兴你进入角色了
Great. Glad you're on it.
一切准备就绪
All systems go!
你为什么要去罗马
Why are you going to Rome?
我在你的储物柜翻到了航班信息
I found the flight information in your locker.
我真是享受现在的状态
I love how everyone
每个人都觉得  我期望在这里保有个人隐私
thinks it's so quaint and childlike of me
是个相当奇怪而幼稚的想法
to expect a modicum of privacy around here.
你明天就飞了
Your flight's tomorrow.
罗马那里有什么急事
What's so urgent in Rome?
我听说他们想拆除罗马竞技场
I hear they want to tear down the coliseum
来建个卡拉OK酒吧
to build a karaoke bar.
罗马的希望医疗中心
The Buona Speranza Medical Center in Rome
正在进行亨廷顿舞蹈症的试验性治疗
is doing a huntington's trial.
说真的  我生来就是唱歌的料
Seriously, I live to sing.
我听说他们在尝试胎儿神经移植
I know that they've been doing fetal neural transplantation.
我还听说他们的试验对象
I also know that their subjects
颅内出血的风险将大幅提高
have increased risk of intracranial hemorrhage.
你不该在这个阶段参加试验性治疗
This isn't the time to join a trial.
这项研究才刚刚起步
This research is in its infancy.
你的病症也只在初期
So's your condition.
你看了我的备忘录
You read my note.
你翻过我的储物柜
You go through my locker.
然后你打算给我上人生选择课
And then you decide you want to round it off
做为结尾吗
by lecturing me on my life choices?
我很担心你
I'm worried about you.
是啊  这样就说得通了
Oh. Well, that makes it all right then.
现在是怎样
So what, exactly, is this?
如果你愿意
It can still be open and casual
我们的关系可以依然开放  随性而有趣
and fun if you want.
开放
Open?
你觉得我想有其他人介入吗
You think I want to see other people?
但昨天晚上  你很情绪化
Well, last night was emotional for you.
我们都失去了那位病人  我们眼看着人们死去
We both lost that patient. We watched people die.
我回到这里  求助于维科丁
I came back here and I went for the vicodin,
而你  你甩了你的未婚夫追到这里来
And you...dumped your fiance and you came here.
我一点也不后悔
Which I don't regret.
我没说你后悔了
I'm not saying you do.
我是说你这样太冲动了
I'm just saying it was an impulsive move.
别这样
Don't do this.
你为什么就爱把事情分析的那么透彻呢
Why do you have to analyze things to death?
为什么不能  让它美好着呢
Why can't you just... let it be nice?
说得对
You're right.
都怪这个讨厌秘密的浴缸
That was very anti-secret bath.
豪斯
House.
怎么了
Yeah.
这次神秘的洗浴
The secret bath is...
正在燃烧我的私处
Burning my lady parts.
你觉得我的肛门感觉如何呢
How do you think my anus feels?
灼热说明它在起作用
Burning means it's working.
我们能不泡了吗
Can we get out now?
就等你说这句话了
I was so waiting for you to say that.
请问Jankowski医生在吗
Can I speak to Dr. Jankowski?
不用  在百慕大群岛的话就算了
No. I don't need to disturb him in Bermuda.
一切都顺利吗
Everything okay?
卡迪医生的电话始终转接到语音信箱
Dr. Cuddy's phone keeps going directly to voicemail,
我需要一位神经外科医生
and I need to get a neurosurgeon
为理查森医生代班
to replace Dr. Richardson for the day
不然她就惨了
or else she's screwed.
我就是神经外科医生
I'm a neurosurgeon.
不  你不是
No. You're not.
我经常为病人做开颅手术
I've cut into people's heads more often--
你在墨尔本大学期间
You did a residency in neurosurgery
参加过神经外科医生的住院实习
at the University of Melbourne,
但你没有专科资格
But you were never board-certified.
你只在这里上了两天班  怎么
You've worked here two days. How--
卡迪医生给我的第一项任务
Dr. Cuddy's first assignment was for me to get to know
就是摸清豪斯医生手下的底细
everything about Dr. House's team...
她关照我千万不要相信你们说的鬼话
And not to believe anything any of them told me.
我  不算神经外科医生吗
I'm...not a neurosurgeon?
看
And...voila!
第一道菜
The first course,
我把嫩小麦穗切片
I flaked some tender young ears of corn
旁边是配菜  外国早餐肉
on the side of assorted exotic breakfast meats
淋上了少量辣椒酱
in a chile sauce reduction.
第二道菜呢
And the... second course?
一颗葡萄  擦盘子用
A single grape. To cleanse the palate.
好像有些浪费  不过没有第三道菜了
Which is kind of a waste, 'cause there is no third course.
很高兴我们没有出去
I'm glad we stayed in.
这一切  真不错
This is actually... pretty good.
我总是能知道你什么时候在说谎
I can always tell when you lie.
屡试不爽
I mean always.
我和我大一室友睡过
I slept with my freshman roommate.
-说谎  -实话
- A lie. - A truth.
-你有个小动作  -什么
- You have a tell.  - What is it?
先承认你在说谎
First admit that you were lying.
好嘛  我说谎了
Fine. I was lying.
我的性交史非常无趣
My sexual history is boring and predictable.
-我的小动作是什么  -你开什么玩笑
- What is my tell?  - Are you kidding?
如果我告诉了你  你就会改掉它
If I tell you your tell, you'll get rid of it,
那我就没那么神了
Then I won't be able to tell.
那你也得告诉我
Well, then you have to tell me something
我所不了解的你
I don't already know about you.
尽管如此  技术上来说  你也没告诉我
Even though, technically, you didn't tell me something
我所不了解的你
that I didn't already know about you.
别再这么逻辑狂  就说些什么吧
Quit being so damn logical and just tell me.
我曾与相片中的你
I used to have an intimate relationship
有过一段亲密的感情
with a photograph of you.
实际上  还有一只袜子
Well, actually, a sock and a photograph.
我知道
I know.
我在说谎
I was lying.
在万圣节我打扮成睡美人时你拍的照片
The photo you took of me as sleeping beauty on Halloween.
不然你为什么要拍那张照片
Why else would you take that picture?
我要解个手
I have to pee.
你也学会了吧
Ha! You can tell.
实际上我想拉粑粑
'cause actually, I have to poo.
什么事
What?
卡迪的助理  决定开动自己的小脑筋解决问题
Cuddy's assistant decided to use his own brain.
谁给他灌输这愚蠢的主意的
Who put that idiot idea into his head?
你也可以听听这个意见啊
Perhaps you could follow the same advice.
他通知了公共卫生属
He notified DPH that
说这里没有在班的神经外科医生
there's no neurosurgeon on the premises.
他说法律规定他这么做  他也的确这么做了
Said he legally had to, which he legally had to.
听起来一切在你掌握之中啊
Sounds like you got the situation under control.
不  我没有
No. I don't.
你知道我没有
You know I don't.
等公共卫生属的人到这里  他们就会关了急诊室
When DPH shows up, they're gonna shut down our E.R.
根本没办法  就这样了  豪斯
This can't be fixed. It is what it is, House.
很好  我完全有理由相信
Great. I've got every faith
你有能力搞定这一切
in your ability to solve the problem.
我给45英里范围以内的
I have called every neurosurgeon
神经外科医生都打过电话了  一无所获
within a 45-mile radius -- nothing.
我觉得豪斯不过是在测试我们
I think House is just testing us.
他一直都在测试我们
He's always testing us.
不管是不是测试  这是个问题
Test or not, it's a problem.
这又不是我们的问题
It's not our problem.
这又怎么会是豪斯的问题
Why the hell is it House's problem?
卡迪到底在哪里
Where the hell is Cuddy?
我们要么报告此事
We either report this,
然后半间医院歇业
and half the hospital gets shut down,
要么我们隐瞒此事  冒个险
or we cover it up and run the risk
运气不好的话整间医院都要歇业
that the entire hospital gets shut down.
或者去找理查森
Or we get Richardson.
他病了
He's sick.
我们是医生  我们能让病人好起来
And we're doctors. We get people better.
石头剪刀布
Fing fong fooey?
能睁眼了吗
Can I open them yet?
再等一下
Just a second.
好了  把手伸出来
Okay. Hold out your hand.
我一直都想用这种东西
I always wanted to open a bottle of champagne
给香槟开瓶
with one of these things.
站我后面
You might wanna stand behind me for this.
准备好了
Okay...
这下好了
Yeah!
我想我大概
Mm, I think I might have...
哪里弄错了
got that slightly wrong.
好在我总算尝试过了
Well, good thing I got a case.
豪斯  开门
House, open up.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
让他进来吧
Just let him in.
不行
No.
豪斯
House!
如果我们不理他  他会走的
If we just ignore him, he'll go away.
豪斯
House!
我想他应该走了
I think he finally left.
以防万一他还没有离开
But just in case he hasn't,
我们能做些什么不用讲话的事呢
what can we do that does not involve talking?
你开了我的铃声
You turned on my ringer!
我知道你在里边
I know you're in there.
我都听见你手机响了
I can hear your cell phone ringing.
-让他进来吧  -不
- just let him in.- no!
他就跟个流浪狗似的...
He's like a stray...
会吃掉所有东西  到处糟蹋
He'll eat everything,shed all over the place,
在地板上拉屎
And crap on the floor.
您好  我是格利高里·豪斯
Hi. This is gregory house.
我现在不能接电话  有事请留言
I can't take your call at the moment. Please leave a message.
如果是威尔逊  我很好  没有自杀
If this is wilson, I'm fine, not suicidal,
没有吸毒
Not on drugs,
没有因病人去世而无法自拔
Coping very well with the loss of my last patient.
所以别担心  忙你的去吧
So feel free to go about your day without worry.
滴
Beep!
豪斯
House...
你不能不去上班啊
You can't just not show up to work.
卡迪会怎么说你
What's cuddy gonna say?
如果还是威尔逊...
If this is still wilson...
她放了我一天假
She gave me the day off.
还有明天
And tomorrow.
好吧  也许明天不放
Okay, maybe not tomorrow.
但今天  我很好
But today. I'm fine.
现在  请走吧
Now, go away.
滴
Beep!
如果你明天不上班  我还会来的
If you're not in tomorrow, I'll be back.
听着  你是我们唯一的神经外科医生
Look, you're the only neurosurgeon we've got.
你得赶紧好起来  回医院去
You have to suck it up and go back to the hospital.
我们不用你做手术  回去就行
We're not asking you to operate, just to be there.
除非你能给我搬上这个马桶
Unless you can transport this t-toilet with me,
否则我不出门
I'm not leaving the room.
我给你带个桶
I'll get a bucket.
你不知道问题所在
You're missing the point.
我吃了次品寿司  病了  你们走吧
I ate bad sushi. I'm sick. Go away.
我们可以给你用异丙嗪止吐
We can give you promethazine for the nausea.
吃过了
Already took it.
还有曲美苄胺
And trimethobenzamide.
可能不是食物中毒
Maybe this isn't food poisoning.
不管怎样
Whatever it is,
肯定是伤到了他的胃壁
It must have damaged the lining of his stomach.
如果不治好  什么都不顶用
Till that heals, nothing's gonna work.
所以我们得治好胃壁和呕吐
So we need to treat both that and the nausea.
不管他究竟出了什么问题
And whatever's wrong with him.
我们给他用安丹司琼和前列腺素吧
We give him ondansetron and prostaglandins.
不管他究竟出了什么问题的话
And whatever's wrong with him.
这两种药都不是能治疗
Neither of those will treat
他可能患上的病
Any possible underlying condition.
管他的  他又不是我们的病人
Who cares? He's not our patient.
是医院的
The hospital is.
我能  听见你们说话
I can...hear you.
你非常痛苦  不是吗
You're pretty miserable, aren't you?
你想吃一种有点危险的
Would you be willing to take a...fairly risky drug
但有可能让你的症状全部消失的药吗
If it would make it all go away?
为什么不让他进来
Why didn't you let him in?
我们做爱的时候你也想着威尔森吗
You were thinking about wilson while we were having sex?
酷毕了  我也是
That's so cool!So was I.
你把我藏起来  为什么
You were hiding me from him. Why?
我不是金屋藏娇
I was not hiding you.
我是在保护你的隐私权
I was protecting your privacy.
我不确定你是不是准备好在公众前
Wasn't sure if you were ready to go public
暴露"咱俩"的事儿
With the whole..."us" Thing yet.
如果我想要隐私的话
Why would I be doing all this
还干嘛这样
If I wanted it to be private? Ohh...
我从没要求过
Oh. I never even asked.
可能是你还没准备好
Maybe you're not ready yet.
你看过那药的副作用说明了吗
Have you read the list of side effects on those drugs?
可能会让他血压失调
We could crash his bp.
我没听见动静
I haven't heard a thump,
所以我猜他还在安静地呕吐
So I assume he's still quietly puking.
可能情况更糟呢
We could be making him worse.
从大局着想
Bigger picture--
我们是为了让医院更好
We're making the hospital better.
我们可以给他做所有你想做的检测
We can test for whatever you want to test him for once
只要他稳定了  能回到医院去
He's stable enough to get back to the hospital.
别腻歪了  走啊
Now, stop being a girl and move.
那么接下来你该问我这次的亨廷顿病治疗了
So you gonna ask me about this huntington's trial,
顺便也问问你  能给我些建议吗
And by ask, I mean give me your opinion?
没  但有件事
No. There is one thing,though.
你会和我做爱吗
Will you have sex with me?
-什么  -这次治疗意味着你要马上离开
- What?  - well, this trial means you're leaving right away.
我等了很久了
I was playing a long game.
期限将尽啊
Deadlines have been moved up.
那玩意不错
Wow. That stuff is good.
我想你能回医院了吧
Think you might back to the hospital?
当然  那灯真亮
Uh-huh. That lamp is shiny.
我是说  亮的真...
I mean, the way it shines is...
璀璨
Shiny.
我觉得这是药的某种副作用
I take it this is one of the side effects of the drugs.
管他呢  走吧
Who cares? Let's go.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你以为我怕让人知道吗
You think I'm afraid to go public?
我要证明你错了
I'm gonna prove you wrong.
用三脚架证明吗
With a tripod?
用性爱录像带  把这个送给威尔逊
With a sex tape. We'll send it to wilson.
一箭双雕啊  咱俩再做一遍
It's a win-win. We get to do it again,
而且...  没准他还能学到些东西
And...he might actually learn something.
听起来像是有人要破门而入
It sounds like someone's trying to break in.
可能没事的
It's probably nothing.
待在这儿
Stay here.
卡住了吗
Hey. Stuck?
笨蛋  看起来很痛苦啊
Bummer. Looks painful.
菊花茶还是英式早餐
Chamomile or english breakfast?
你能靠谱点  先拉我下来吗
Would you stop being an ass and pull me out of here?
你刚才没听到我的留言吗
You didn't get my message earlier?
听到了  但就像某人曾告诉我的
Yeah. But as someone once told me,
每个人都会撒谎
Everybody lies.
我很好
I'm fine.
只是待在家里  放松一下
Just staying home,chill-laxin'.
你的病人死了
Your patient died,
你不接我电话  还不开门
You ignore my calls, and you won't open the door.
我不觉得你没事
I don't think you're fine.
我想你可能在一年没吸毒后又复吸了
I think you might be throwing away a drug-free year.
或者  我不理你是因为其他原因
Or...I'm ignoring you for a different reason.
和我的女朋友做爱
Sex with my girlfriend.
请您能让我  让我先进来吗
Hmm.Will you please just-- please let me in?
谢谢
Thank you.
什么时候你把妓女
And since when did you start referring to hookers
称作女朋友了呢
as girlfriends?
她不是妓女
She's not a hooker.
什  什么  真的吗
What are--wha--really?
名字开头是"卡"  结尾是"迪"
Begins with "C", ends with uddy.
你到底吃了多少维可丁啊
How many vicodin have you taken?
我是说真的
I'm serious.
卡迪和我现在是一对了
Cuddy and I are now cuddy and I.
我是卡迪的了
There's an "I" In cuddy.
豪斯  别在意
House...it's okay.
几乎所有的瘾君子都会复吸几次
Almost all addicts relapse a few times.
她在我的卧室
She's in my bedroom.
你正在幻觉之中  豪斯
You're hallucinating, House.
亲爱的  我们有伙伴光临了
Honey buns! We got company.
瞳孔正常  脉搏正常
Pupils are normal. Pulse is normal.
比正常要更好
Better than that.
他们都相当的棒
They're both totally awesome.
我没有用药
I'm not on drugs.
那么你为什么要说卡迪那段谎呢
So...why did you lie about Cuddy?
来表达观点
To make a point.
也许是与让你闭嘴有关
Probably something to do with shutting you up.
是我的原意
It's my go-to idea.
你看起来还好  要我留下来吗
You do seem okay. You want me to stick around?
如果让你感觉好一些的话
I could do my usual thing
我可以像平常一样
Of pretending I like watching monster truck rallies,
假装喜欢看暴力卡车拉力赛
If that would make you feel better.
不用  你走吧
No. You go.
豪斯  你可能会死的
House...you could have died.
你的病人也确实在你怀里死去
You had a patient who did die in your arms.
你此刻不该孤独渡过
You shouldn't be alone.
我知道  所以我召妓
I know. That's why I called a hooker.
现在你可以滚了
Now, go away.
因为你会显得多余
'cause... you'll be extra.
你真的没事吗
Are you really okay?
你想再闯入我家吗
Are you gonna break in again?
你查过我的脉搏和瞳孔了
You checked my pulse. You checked my pupils.
我会给你寄我的尿液样本
I'll mail you the urine sample.
我怎么从来没见过你们
How come I've never even met you guys?
你们好像是最厉害的人
Y-you're like the greatest...
你知道荧光灯
Guys. You know fluorescent lights
闪烁的频率跟人脑是一样的
Flicker at the same frequency as the human brain?
你知道人脑是不会闪烁的
You know the human brain doesn't flicker?
不需要脑外科医生来判断
Doesn't take a brain surgeon to figure out
他不能做脑外科手术
That he can't perform brain surgery.
他怎么回事
What's wrong with him?
高  血糖
High...blood sugar.
我们给他补水后他就会好的
He'll be fine as soon as we rehydrate him.
那就好
That's a relief.
感谢上帝
Thank god.
Dph的人20分钟内会到这儿
Dph guy will be here in 20 minutes.
他是怎么回事儿
What is wrong with him?
高血糖
High blood sugar.
你刚才是这么说的
You just said so.
奇斯在做测试
Chase is running labs.
现在最可能的是肝炎
Right now the top two contenders are hepatitis
还有胃溃疡
And peptic ulcer disease.
所以  今天真的是你最后一天在这吗
So...is today really your last day?
明天飞机
Flying out tomorrow.
你请了多长的假啊
How long a leave are you taking?
难说
Depends.
药物测试  听起来很冒险
On the drug trial. Sounds risky.
唠叨唠叨
Yadda, yadda.
你觉得我不应该去试
You don't think I should do it.
知道了
Message heard.
不  我很赞同
No. I approve.
在早逝之前享乐是胡说
Living fast and dying young is crap.
如果你可以好起来的话
If you have a chance to get better...
我觉得那很好
I say good for you.
我让威尔森进来是专门要公布这件事
I brought wilson in here specifically to go public,
像你要求的那样
Just like you requested.
我给你压力
I pressured you.
威尔森从窗户进来也给你压力
Wilson coming through the window pressured you.
如果你是被逼的  不会有好结果的
If you're forced into this, it's not gonna work.
你对此有什么回应吗
Do you have any response to that?
游戏开始
Game on.
-他好点了吗  -是的
- Is he better? - Yep.
你又在说谎了对吧
You're lying to me again, aren't you?
-是的  -那我们糟了
- Yep. - Then we're screwed.
我们不是应该告诉
Don't we have to tell--
噢  真不巧
Oh! Damn.
理查森医生正准备做手术
Dr. Richardson's prepping for surgery.
我得跟他谈谈
Yeah. I need to talk to him.
-他在准备做手术  -我听到了
- He's prepping for surgery. - So you said.
我只是得确认他是你所说的医生
I just need to confirm he is who you say he is
还有他是个持证的神经外科医生
And that he's a licensed neurosurgeon.
这里是他的文件
Well, here's his paperwork.
他的医院身份证在这里
His hospital ID is right there.
你可以看到  就是他
You can...see it's him.
对  我仍旧需要跟他谈谈
Yeah. I should still talk to him.
他们已经消毒过  他又要重新消毒
They've already scrubbed. He'd have to be re-sterilized.
病人的麻醉又要重新弄
The patient's anesthesia would have to be adjusted.
你为什么跟我说他不在
Why did you report he wasn't here?
那必然是误会
I must have... misunderstood.
噢  为什么
Oh...why...
为什么
Why...
为什么里面那么热
Why is it so... so hot in there?
啦滴哒
La-dee-dah.
Woodstock音乐节  宝贝
Woodstock, baby.
他醉了吗
Is he stoned?
不  我们很肯定他是
No. We're pretty sure he's got--
我很肯定你们会解释
Oh, I'm sure you have an explanation,
可是我不在乎
But I don't care.
看  你们必须有神经外科医生在楼里
See, you need to have a doctor on the premises
而且这人必须可以做神经外科手术
Who can actually do neurosurgery.
告诉护理转移所有的急救
Tell the attending to divert all ambulances away
并联系其他医院
And start calling other hospitals
看哪家医院可以接手病情稳定的重病看护室的病人
And see who can take your stabilized ICU patients.
那些部门都要关闭
Those departments are shutting down.
-设计这个词得五分  -明白了
- "Design" For five points. - Got it.
-听  -明白  两个版本都有
- "Hear." - Got it. Both versions.
爱情
"Love."
你没见到爱情
You didn't see love.
诶  我可不知道你会因我桌面游戏不好
Wow. I didn't think you'd take
而判断我的态度
My lack of board game skills so personally.
你为什么不告诉我你爱我
Why didn't you tell me you loved me?
不是曾经有个睿智的女人说过
Didn't a wise woman once say--
这个曾经指的是两个小时前
And by once, I mean two hours ago--
为什么你死都要要分析一切事情呢
"Why do you have to analyze everything to death?
为什么不能认为这就是好的呢
Why can't this just be nice?"
我告诉过你我爱你
I told you I loved you.
你没有回应我
You didn't tell me you loved me back.
你不觉得我会担心吗
You don't think that should give me cause for concern?
不  因为语言并不重要
No. 'cause words don't matter.
重要的是行动
Actions matter.
你就这样执拗
You're really gonna take a stand here.
-你就不能说  -不能
- You can't say-- - nope.
为什么
Why?
因为
Because...
我忘了拿一个V
I forgot to grab a "V."
耳垂
Lobe.
给你一分
Gets you one point.
一分
One.
所有测试结果都是阴性
Labs show he's negative for everything.
我猜至少有一个是错的
I'm guessing at least one of them is wrong.
谁在乎呢  急诊室和重症病房
Who cares? The R.R. And the ICU
都搬空了一半了  里面都是穿西装的人
Are half-empty and the place is crawling with suits.
已经完了
It's over.
你知道我们还有个病人在这儿
You do know we still have a sick patient here.
对吧  他就是那个在你后面坐着
Right? He's the guy sitting
随时有脱掉衣服的人
Right behind you, taking off his clothes again.
呃  喂喂
Uh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你为什么不坐下来
Uh, why don't you just sit down
冷静点
And take it easy?
他现在本该恢复正常了
He should be coming down by now.
可是我没有
And yet...I'm not.
要是他的行为
What if his behavior
并不是昂丹斯琼的副作用
Isn't a side effect of the ondansetron?
-要是这是个症状  -谢了
- What if it's a symptom? - Thank you.
什么引起的精神错乱和恶心
What causes delirium and nausea?
他被关在医院几天了
He's been stuck here in the hospital a few days.
没有其他人感染  所以不是环境毒素
Nobody else is sick, so it can't be environmental.
并没有被困住  我偷偷溜走了
Not exactly stuck. I snuck out.
自由是天生的权利
Freedom is my birthright.
你去哪儿了
Where did you go?
-会展中心的海鲜节  -我们惨了
- The seafood festival at the convention center. - We're screwed.
海鲜节上有从全世界来的食物
Seafood festival has stuff from all around the world
还有各种想不到的食物组合
In combinations nobody ever thought of.
我们可以想一年
We could be here all year.
-吃过虾吗  -有的
- You had shrimp? - Uh-huh.
-蟹和龙虾呢  -也有
- And crab? Lobster? - Uh-huh.
还有呢
Uh-huh. And...
什么看起来好吃我都有吃
I ate whatever looked good.
有吃鱼子吗
Did you eat any roe?
-小小鱼子  -好好吃
- Little tiny eggs? - Yummy!
蟾蜍子可以引起恶心  而且狂热
Toad eggs will cause nausea, and they can get you high.
如果我没错  解毒剂是最快的
If I'm right, the antidote is fast-acting.
如果我们可以让他短时间内不脱衣服
If we can get him to keep his clothes on long enough,
他就可以作为一个神经外科医生通过测试
He can pass as a functioning neurosurgeon.
法国
France.
不是巴黎或里韦拉
And not paris or the rivera,
可是这有个地方在诺曼底
But there's this place in normandy.
在一个有潮汐的岛屿上
It's on a... A tidal island.
那些不住在其中一个小旅店的人
Everyone who's not staying in one of the small inns
必须在涨潮之前离开
Has to leave before the tide comes in.
你就可以独自霸占这个九百年历史的堡垒
You have this 900-year-old fortress all to yourself.
它的名字叫做
It's called...
圣米歇尔山
Mont saint-michel?
就是它  你去过那里吗
That's it. Have you been there?
没有  可是我知道它什么样子
Nope. But I got a pretty good idea what it looks like.
你怎么知道的
H-how did you know?
你以前用来做屏保
You used to have a picture of it as a screensaver.
那是好几年之前了
That was years ago.
我猜那是个值得纪念的地方
I guess it's a memorable place.
可惜我们现在不可以直接飞到诺曼底去
Now, unfortunately, we can't fly straight to normandy,
不过中途在伦敦转机不过几个小时
But the layover in london's only a couple of hours.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
都在这里了
It's all there.
你只要点击确认
All you gotta do is click confirm,
我们就可以去吃羊角面包了
And we're eating croissant
明天这个时候就能得到
and being insulted by stinky people
那些臭脾气的法国人无礼对待
this time tomorrow.
别担心  我用的是威尔森的信用卡
Don't worry. I used Wilson's credit card.
不行
I can't.
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
我用的是你的信用卡
I used your credit card.
豪斯...
House...
医院不需要你人在
The hospital does not need your body.
可我需要  我女儿也需要我
I do. So does my daughter.
她也可以来
Well, she can come too.
或者跑去外婆家呆两天
Or to grandmother's house she can go.
这也太不切实际
This is crazy.
你可以解除婚约
So...you break off your engagement,
却不能调整一下行程吗
but you won't adjust your schedule.
不行
I can't.
至少明天不行
Not...tomorrow.
但半个月后应该
But...two weekends from now.
如果蕾切尔要和我母亲呆在一起
If Rachel's gonna stay with my mom,
我还需要准备一段时间
I'm gonna need a little bit of prep time.
好吧
Okay.
要是这药不管用
What if it doesn't work?
我的下半辈子会不会都这样
What if I stay this way forever?
解毒剂效用很快  如果我们是对的
The antidote works quickly. If we're right,
你很快就会变回原来的你
you should be back to your old self in no time.
原来的我很无聊
My old self was boring.
难道就不能保持现在的我
Can't we keep the new self?
躺好  别解扣子
Just lay down, and stop unbuttoning.
我很抱歉看了你的字条
I'm sorry that I read your note
翻了你的衣柜
and looked in your locker.
时间长就会习惯的
You get used to that kind of thing around here.
有人陪你一起去罗马
Do you have anyone going with you to Rome?
你是在拐着弯的问我
Is that your passive-aggressive way
有没有交往对象
of asking me if I'm seeing somebody else?
我希望你有
I hope you are.
我的意思是希望能有个人陪着你
I mean...I hope you have someone with you.
连我都很怕
If I'm scared about this,
我不敢想象你现在的感觉
I can't imagine how you must feel.
你不该独自承受
You shouldn't be alone.
如果你需要的话
If you want...
我可以陪你过去呆几天
I could fly over for a few days.
以朋友的身份
Friends.
谢谢你
I appreciate that,
我会没事的
but I think I'll be okay.
绕了个大圈  我们最后还是
I guess we took the long way around
成了朋友
to being friends, huh?
是啊  做朋友
I guess we all did.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为你所做的一切
For everything.
不客气
You're welcome.
一切的一切
For everything.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
我确实该走了
I really do have to leave.
我知道
I know.
怎么了
What's the problem?
我们俩合不来的
This isn't gonna work.
就这样吗
That's it?
你不能就说这么一句  就不说了
You can't just... say that and shut up.
因为这是在陈述事实
It's just a statement of fact.
而不是有争议性的命题
It's not a debatable proposition.
是啊  因为你能预见未来
Right. Because you can see the future.
不是  但我能审视过去
No. But I can see the past.
你也会记起
And you're gonna remember
我对你的伤害
all the horrible things I've done,
然后你再试着说服自己告诉自己
and you're gonna try to convince yourself
说我已经改过
that I've changed.
接着我还会再做伤害你的事
And I'm gonna start doing those horrible things again,
因为我并没有改变
because I haven't changed.
接着你会意识到  对于一个单身母亲
Then you'll realize that...
选择和我在一起是一件多么荒唐的事
I'm an insane choice for someone who has a kid.
最终就会
And from there,
自然而然地总结出
it's a short step to the inevitable conclusion
这所有的一切
that all of this...
都只是个错误
was a mistake.
我刚才说的话哪一句不是真的
Tell me any of that isn't true.
一下子转去仁爱医院这么多人
Mercy doesn't have enough room in their ICU
他们可能没有这么多的重症监护室  所以...
to handle the overflow, so--
那就用不着你费心了
Don't worry about it.
据说您想与我们的神经外科医生
I believe you wanted to talk to dr. Richardson,
理查森医生谈谈
our neurosurgeon?
很抱歉刚才与您在如此尴尬的情形下见面
I'm sorry that we met under such trying circumstances.
希望我们可以恢复为一等外伤中心医院
I hope you restore our rating as a level one trauma center
即刻重开急救中心和重症监护
and reopen the E.R. and the ICU immediately.
一起意外的食物中毒
An accidental case of poisoning.
理查森医生已被治愈
Dr. Richardson has been treated
并可以随时开始工作
and is ready to resume work.
用你的食指触碰鼻尖
Touch your nose with your index finger
并告诉我  你将如何治疗脑挫伤
and tell me how you treat a cerebral contusion.
我会观察是否出现水肿
Uh, I-I-I would watch for oedema
及小脑幕裂孔疝现象
and transtentorial herniation.
好极了
Good enough.
准许你们的请求
Turn it around.
你得加班啦
You're gonna be up late.
下次  记住要逃避责任
Next time... avoid responsibility.
吃蛋糕去
Cake?
陶博认为我们大家应该为你饯行
Taub thought we should have a little party
开个小聚会
to see you off properly.
他对这种事总是故作深情
He gets sentimental about these things.
真不应该给他看我的胸部
I never should have flashed him.
说到这个
Speaking of which...
刚才我问你想不想
earlier today I asked you about...
做爱的事
having sex.
你给了我一个
You gave me a look
我几乎确定是拒绝的表情
that almost certainly could only mean no.
但在没问清楚之前就放弃
However, on the other hand, I'd be remiss if I...
我会有点不甘心
didn't follow up and confirm.
看吧  又是这个表情
See? It's the same look.
如果这表情第一次不意味着拒绝
So if it didn't mean no the first time,
-那么这次...  -不行
- then...  - no.
不行  绝对不行
No. No, no.
别有负担
No pressure.
你这招管用过
Does that method ever work?
不止一次
At least once.
这种暗示有点乱
Mm, I'm, um... getting mixed signals.
一会吃蛋糕见
See you at the cake.
每当你快乐的时候
The only time you're afraid
你都会担心
is when you're happy.
你不期望这种快乐继续
You just don't expect it to last.
因为不能永远快乐
'Cause it doesn't.
你并不知道
You don't know that.
我曾经伤害过你
I've done horrible things to you.
我还会再次伤害你的
And I'll do horrible things again to you.
仅仅是因为一个死去的女孩和一堆石子
But because of one stupid moment
还有那么愚蠢的一刻
with a dying girl and a pile of rubble...
你就认为我能改
you think I can change.
告诉我  我有哪里说错了吗
Tell me where I'm wrong.
我不想你改变
I don't want you to change.
我知道你的人生一团糟
I know you're screwed up.
我也知道不管怎样你都会很糟
I know you are always gonna be screwed up.
但你是我见过的最了不起的人
But you're the most incredible man I've ever known.
你也永远会是我见过的
You are always gonna be...
最了不起的人
the most incredible man I have ever known.
所以除非你要跟我分手
So unless you're breaking up with me,
现在我要回家
I am going home now.
我爱你
I love you.
十三哪儿去了
Where's thirteen?
她不会来了
I don't think she's coming.
怎么了
What's going on?
她也不会去罗马
She's not going to Rome.
你说她改主意了
You mean she changed her mind?
我打给罗马的医院
I called the hospital in Rome
想查一下她的手术日程
to see when she was schedule for surgery.
-你为什么要...  -这都不重要
- Why would you...  - Doesn't matter.
重要的是  她都没参加临床试验
Point is, she's not even in the trial.
对方从没听过这个名字
Never heard of her.
她一整天都在骗我们
She's been lying to us all day.
那你给她...
Well, have you tried...
手机和座机都打不通
Both her phone lines have been disconnected.
她就这么走了
She's just gone.
一切都会好起来的
It's gonna be great.